<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ampersand-Game on Tabletop Ergonomics</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/ampersand-game/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ampersand-Game on Tabletop Ergonomics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>CC BY-SA 4.0</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 13:26:09 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/ampersand-game/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Start Breaking My Heart</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/start-breaking-my-heart/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 13:26:09 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/start-breaking-my-heart/</guid>
      <description>high level intro&#xA;do you like D&amp;amp;D (folk tradition) but not D&amp;amp;D (published rules) or D&amp;amp;D (play culture) or D&amp;amp;D (lifestyle brand)? does changing the name of the game cause shifts in your players&amp;rsquo; behavior or your own? maybe you just like looking at different games for fun and stealing the bits you like. here are cool games you might want to check out&#xA;games which belong in the NSR cauldron&amp;rsquo;s #modern-dnd channel.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Slappers Only!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/slappers-only/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 13:40:51 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/slappers-only/</guid>
      <description>Original Doc by deldon. Text has been edited by Window Dump.&#xA;This is a curated collection of the official optional rules in D&amp;amp;D 2014 (aka 5e &amp;lsquo;14) culled from the DMG and PHB to create a simpler, more streamlined game. These rules should be compatible with many other similar games including D&amp;amp;D 2024 (5e &amp;lsquo;24), Tales of the Valiant, and Level Up!: Advanced 5e.&#xA;Editorial editions Additions to the original text are in these helpful admonition boxes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>You can fix 5e!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/you-can-fix-5e/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 14:53:32 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/you-can-fix-5e/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s start with some background &amp;ndash; I&amp;rsquo;ve taken a somewhat unusual route to arrive here. Technically, the first RPG I was exposed to was D&amp;amp;D 3E, but the first RPG I actually read and fell in love with was Risus. Note that Risus has a drastically different approach to mechanics and style compared to other traditional RPG&amp;rsquo;s: it&amp;rsquo;s a rules-light comedy game. Despite almost zero experience with running games, I printed out its six pages and had an incredible session on a camping trip with crazy, collaborative worldbuilding.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I Don&#39;t Like 5e</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/i-dont-like-5e/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2025 13:45:10 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/i-dont-like-5e/</guid>
      <description>Wow, random dweeb on the internet from a subculture resents the largest and most popular aspect of his subculture that&amp;rsquo;s acknowledged in mainstream media. What&amp;rsquo;s next, an essay about how drum &amp;amp; bass ruined jungle?&#xA;Let&amp;rsquo;s start by placing all of the issues with Hasbro and Wizards of the Coast into a box labeled &amp;ldquo;art under capitalism&amp;rdquo; and move the box out of the scope of this post. No complaints about online-only, subscription-based content: I&amp;rsquo;ll engage with the designers in good faith that they just wanted to make another cool RPG.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
