<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tabletop Ergonomics</title>
    <link>https://windowdump.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Tabletop Ergonomics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>CC BY-SA 4.0</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 16:54:12 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://windowdump.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Endies 2025</title>
      <link>https://windowdump.github.io/posts/endies-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 16:54:12 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://windowdump.github.io/posts/endies-2025/</guid>
      <description>A blogwagon initiative started by Lady Tabletop on the Dice Exploder Discord server that&amp;rsquo;s making a bit of waves, and a way for me to unpack and debrief this year of tabletop RPG obsession.&#xA;This past year I finally managed to actually run a few campaigns! I&amp;rsquo;d like to have an ongoing, long-term game, for now I&amp;rsquo;m happy to have casual pick-up groups meeting regularly with like-minded freaks.&#xA;Pointless Stats I played 4 sessions outdoors.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Slappers Only!</title>
      <link>https://windowdump.github.io/posts/slappers-only/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 13:40:51 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://windowdump.github.io/posts/slappers-only/</guid>
      <description>Original Doc by deldon. Text has been edited by Window Dump.&#xA;This is a curated collection of the official optional rules in D&amp;amp;D 2014 (aka 5e &amp;lsquo;14) culled from the DMG and PHB to create a simpler, more streamlined game. These rules should be compatible with many other similar games including D&amp;amp;D 2024 (5e &amp;lsquo;24), Tales of the Valiant, and Level Up!: Advanced 5e.&#xA;Editorial editions Additions to the original text are in these helpful admonition boxes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Disks &amp; Daemons</title>
      <link>https://windowdump.github.io/posts/disks-n-daemons/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 11:06:41 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://windowdump.github.io/posts/disks-n-daemons/</guid>
      <description>Itch link Disks &amp;amp; Daemons - Screen Version PDF Disks &amp;amp; Daemons - Print Version PDF Disks &amp;amp; Daemons - Singles PDF Source code (Typst) Submission for FIST: JAM OPS V. Designed for FIST but easily hackable for like, Risus or something.&#xA;It&amp;rsquo;s Rogue, Hackers: Heroes of the Computer Revolution, and TRON in a blender with a splash of anti-canon worldbuilding and two splashes of OSR procedures. Dungeon procedures and procedural dungeons.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Longshot City Character Sheet</title>
      <link>https://windowdump.github.io/posts/longshot-city-character-sheet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2025 16:47:32 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://windowdump.github.io/posts/longshot-city-character-sheet/</guid>
      <description>Longshot City character sheet and quick reference - PDF Source code (Typst) Check out Longshot City on Itch.&#xA;The one time I ran this game I had a time-traveling ghost possess an influencer live-streaming a self-replicating robot outbreak so they could use their psychic powers to fight the robots. Later the ghost possessed another hero while he ate drive-thru food so they could both recover with the sustenance.&#xA;Source code discussion This is the first horizontal full-page character sheet I made.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Runic Magic</title>
      <link>https://windowdump.github.io/posts/runic-magic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2025 16:36:39 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://windowdump.github.io/posts/runic-magic/</guid>
      <description>Runic Magic - PDF Source code (Typst) Original text by skander. Shout out to skander&amp;rsquo;s itch, get his version of this document to double your runes.&#xA;Lightweight interpretive magic system. Uses the Runes from the classic Ultima CRPG series. These are the building blocks of Britiannian magic: each spell is made of one or more runes, and casting them in some games requires you to type in the runes for the spell every time you cast it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WoDu Remix Character Sheet</title>
      <link>https://windowdump.github.io/posts/wodu-remix-character-sheet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2024 12:57:47 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://windowdump.github.io/posts/wodu-remix-character-sheet/</guid>
      <description>flare gradient version&#xA;Black &amp;amp; White - PDF Low Ink, Single Contrast - PDF flare, color - PDF Source Code (Typst) Branching off from FIST, I found the neat PbtA + OSR collection on Itch that contains a bunch of games inspired by World of Dungeons (WoDu1), the Dungeon World pre-order bonus that&amp;rsquo;s basically B/X D&amp;amp;D but you do the 2d6 thing from Apocalypse World instead of a d20. Among the collection is Remix (WoDu Remix) which neatly splits the difference between the OSR, storygames, and 5e, and makes me excited every time I crack it open.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FIST Operative Handbook</title>
      <link>https://windowdump.github.io/posts/fist-operative-handbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2024 12:52:47 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://windowdump.github.io/posts/fist-operative-handbook/</guid>
      <description>FIST Operative Handbook - PDF FIST half-letter character sheet - PDF Source Code (Typst) I&amp;rsquo;m a big fan of FIST, a TTRPG about paranormal mercenaries (think Metal Gear) doing jobs for regular people no one else can (or no one else wants to) during the Cold War (think The A-Team). One of my favorite parts is how quickly a character can be generated, and how flavorful these characters are. Check out FISTREF&amp;rsquo;s Random Merc page if you want to see it in action for yourself.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stuff I made</title>
      <link>https://windowdump.github.io/stuff/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 13:09:37 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://windowdump.github.io/stuff/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s some game stuff I made. Source is provided so you can tweak or hack them to your liking. Change fonts, change colors, tweak the words, build a game on top of it. Or print them out and start playing.&#xA;FIST FIST - Freelance Infantry Strike Team, a paranormal mercenary hack of Offworlders. Metal Gear Solid meets The A-Team at John Harper&amp;rsquo;s table.&#xA;Operative Handbook Blog post&#xA;Half-letter character sheet, plus character creation rules and a rules reference.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hello World!</title>
      <link>https://windowdump.github.io/posts/my-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2024 12:55:34 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://windowdump.github.io/posts/my-first-post/</guid>
      <description>This is a test post Hello. This is a post that I might mark as a draft in the near future. It&amp;rsquo;s a testing post that demonstrates various features of this blog and the styles defined for it. I care way too much about this stuff, but I&amp;rsquo;m getting it out of the way so I don&amp;rsquo;t get distracted by it later (I will get distracted by layout and formatting stuff later).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Who is this person</title>
      <link>https://windowdump.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 12:33:01 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://windowdump.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>My handle is Window Dump (check your man pages to learn more about me, I just output the content of a window to a file in text format). I like computers. I figured out how to program them and get them to do increasingly silly stuff - this blog and its content is just the latest example.&#xA;If you&amp;rsquo;re looking for my old fork of KeyZen, a tool used to practice keyboard layouts (i.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
