<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Wodu on Tabletop Ergonomics</title>
    <link>https://windowdump.github.io/tags/wodu/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Wodu on Tabletop Ergonomics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>CC BY-SA 4.0</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2025 11:06:41 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://windowdump.github.io/tags/wodu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Disks &amp; Daemons</title>
      <link>https://windowdump.github.io/posts/disks-n-daemons/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2025 11:06:41 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://windowdump.github.io/posts/disks-n-daemons/</guid>
      <description>Itch link Disks &amp;amp; Daemons - Screen Version PDF Disks &amp;amp; Daemons - Print Version PDF Disks &amp;amp; Daemons - Singles PDF Source code (Typst) Submission for FIST: JAM OPS V.&#xA;It&amp;rsquo;s Rogue, Hackers: Heroes of the Computer Revolution, and TRON in a blender with a splash of anti-canon worldbuilding and two splashes of OSR procedures. Dungeon procedures and procedural dungeons. Other key influences include The Hacker Jargon File and a smattering of other media where you go into a computer network.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Runic Magic</title>
      <link>https://windowdump.github.io/posts/runic-magic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2025 16:36:39 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://windowdump.github.io/posts/runic-magic/</guid>
      <description>Runic Magic - PDF Source code (Typst) Original text by skander. Shout out to skander&amp;rsquo;s itch, get his version of this document to double your runes.&#xA;Lightweight interpretive magic system. Uses the Runes from the classic Ultima CRPG series. These are the building blocks of Britiannian magic: each spell is made of one or more runes, and casting them in some games requires you to type in the runes for the spell every time you cast it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WoDu Remix Character Sheet</title>
      <link>https://windowdump.github.io/posts/wodu-remix-character-sheet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2024 12:57:47 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://windowdump.github.io/posts/wodu-remix-character-sheet/</guid>
      <description>flare gradient version&#xA;Black &amp;amp; White - PDF Low Ink, Single Contrast - PDF flare, color - PDF Source Code (Typst) Branching off from FIST, I found the neat PbtA + OSR collection on Itch that contains a bunch of games inspired by World of Dungeons (WoDu1), the Dungeon World pre-order bonus that&amp;rsquo;s basically B/X D&amp;amp;D but you do the 2d6 thing from Apocalypse World instead of a d20. Among the collection is Remix (WoDu Remix) which neatly splits the difference between the OSR, storygames, and 5e, and makes me excited every time I crack it open.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FIST Operative Handbook</title>
      <link>https://windowdump.github.io/posts/fist-operative-handbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2024 12:52:47 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://windowdump.github.io/posts/fist-operative-handbook/</guid>
      <description>FIST Operative Handbook - PDF FIST half-letter character sheet - PDF Source Code (Typst) I&amp;rsquo;m a big fan of FIST, a TTRPG about paranormal mercenaries (think Metal Gear) doing jobs for regular people no one else can (or no one else wants to) during the Cold War (think The A-Team). One of my favorite parts is how quickly a character can be generated, and how flavorful these characters are. Check out FISTREF&amp;rsquo;s Random Merc page if you want to see it in action for yourself.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
