<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Posts on Tabletop Ergonomics</title>
		<link>https://windowdump.github.io/posts/</link>
		<description>Recent content in Posts on Tabletop Ergonomics</description>
		<generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
		<language>en-us</language>
		<copyright>CC BY-SA 4.0</copyright>
		<lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 11:06:41 -0400</lastBuildDate>
		<atom:link href="https://windowdump.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
		<item>
			<title>Disks &amp; Daemons</title>
			<link>https://windowdump.github.io/posts/disks-n-daemons/</link>
			<pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 11:06:41 -0400</pubDate>
			
			<guid>https://windowdump.github.io/posts/disks-n-daemons/</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[Trifold pamphlet module for FIST set inside the early internet, with a dungeon generator and dungeon procedures crammed inside.]]></description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[
<figure class="webp" ><picture>
          <source srcset="/images/disks-n-daemons-pamphlet-1_hu059501e6aa2ceb546f00f04ccd7c95e6_1862655_1584x1224_fit_q75_h2_box_3.webp" type="image/webp">
          <source srcset="/images/disks-n-daemons-pamphlet-1_hu059501e6aa2ceb546f00f04ccd7c95e6_1862655_1584x1224_fit_q75_bgffffff_box_3.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
          <img src="/images/disks-n-daemons-pamphlet-1_hu059501e6aa2ceb546f00f04ccd7c95e6_1862655_1584x1224_fit_q75_h2_box_3.webp"alt="Disks &amp; Daemons, first page"  width="1584"  height="1224" />
        </picture></figure>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://windowdump.itch.io/disks-and-daemons">Itch link</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/WindowDump/typst-ttrpg/blob/main/disks-n-daemons/pamphlet.pdf">Disks &amp; Daemons - Screen Version PDF</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/WindowDump/typst-ttrpg/blob/main/disks-n-daemons/pamphlet-print.pdf">Disks &amp; Daemons - Print Version PDF</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/WindowDump/typst-ttrpg/blob/main/disks-n-daemons/pamphlet-singles.pdf">Disks &amp; Daemons - Singles PDF</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/WindowDump/typst-ttrpg/tree/main/disks-n-daemons">Source code (Typst)</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Submission for <a href="https://itch.io/jam/fist-jam-ops-v">FIST: JAM OPS V</a>. Designed for <a href="https://claymorerpgs.itch.io/fist">FIST</a> but easily hackable for like, <em>Risus</em> or something.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s <em>Rogue</em>, <em>Hackers: Heroes of the Computer Revolution</em>, and <em>TRON</em> in a blender with a splash of anti-canon worldbuilding and two splashes of OSR procedures. Dungeon procedures and procedural dungeons. Other key influences include <a href="https://github.com/agiacalone/jargonfile/blob/main/historical/jarg1-88-10-04.txt">The Hacker Jargon File</a> and a smattering of media where you go into a computer network.</p>
<h2 id="gaming-tech">Gaming tech</h2>

<figure class="webp" ><picture>
          <source srcset="/images/disks-n-daemons-pamphlet-2_hu267b25363488fc516726bac65d12660e_1646272_1584x1224_fit_q75_h2_box_3.webp" type="image/webp">
          <source srcset="/images/disks-n-daemons-pamphlet-2_hu267b25363488fc516726bac65d12660e_1646272_1584x1224_fit_q75_bgffffff_box_3.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
          <img src="/images/disks-n-daemons-pamphlet-2_hu267b25363488fc516726bac65d12660e_1646272_1584x1224_fit_q75_h2_box_3.webp"alt="Disks &amp; Daemons, second page"  width="1584"  height="1224"  loading="lazy" />
        </picture></figure>
<p>The pamphlet started coming together when I made the spread on the inside. It features a relatively novel floor generator and tables to use with it.</p>
<h3 id="dungeon-generator">Dungeon generator</h3>
<p>This dungeon generator was inspired by two dungeon generators: the method in &ldquo;O5R&rdquo; TTRPG <a href="https://www.fivetorchesdeep.com">Five Torches Deep</a> and the one in <a href="https://roguebasin.com/index.php/Rogue">Rogue</a>, that game that all those other games are kinda like. <em>Five Torches Deep</em> brings the <em>B/X D&amp;D</em> dangerous dungeon crawling to <em>D&amp;D 5e</em>&rsquo;s math scheme. <em>Rogue</em> was inspired by early <em>Dungeons &amp; Dragons</em>, much like the OSR.</p>
<p><em>Five Torches Deep</em> features a generator where you shuffle a Rubik&rsquo;s Cube, then roll it like a d6 and interpret the results. Each color represents a different type of room. I realized that this theoretically gives you similar results to just rolling a d6 for each cell on a 3x3 grid (cubes are cubes, right?). What if you rolled 9 dice and smushed them together into a 3x3 grid? And what if we used different colored dice? There&rsquo;s a novel dungeon generator.</p>
<p><em>Rogue</em> generates a floor by creating a 3x3 grid of random rooms. <a href="https://github.com/Davidslv/rogue/blob/master/rooms.c#L31">Exact logic</a>: up to 3 rooms are marked as &ldquo;gone&rdquo; (simply not there); rooms have a (dungeon level - 1) in 10 chance to be a dark room, and a 1 in 15 chance to be a maze, otherwise they&rsquo;re open lit rooms; rooms have a 50% chance to contain gold, and a 25% chance to contain a monster &ndash; 80% if the room contains gold too. I had to look up these exact numbers, but I&rsquo;ve played a bit of <em>Rogue</em> &ndash; enough to get bored with its level generator because I&rsquo;m spoiled by <em>Diablo</em>.</p>
<p>Using two colors of dice gives me the same effect as &ldquo;gone&rdquo; rooms to <em>Five Torches Deep</em>, at the cost of only one more D6 table!</p>
<p>The real meat is the table entries, which are little prompts for what&rsquo;s in the room. There&rsquo;s no overarching plot here, instead hints of strange things happening and the squad being hunted by the powers that control this space. This could provide a jumping-off point for a further campaign (pick something the players latch onto) or diversion from another game.</p>
<p>I should probably demonstrate what prepping this actually looks like. The stocking procedures are <em>not</em> playtested. I also don&rsquo;t clarify what the exit doors look like - I was imaging picking an exterior wall (or interior to be weird) and deciding that wall had the exit.</p>
<h3 id="other-procedures">Other procedures</h3>
<p>For an OSR dungeon crawling experience, I added a few lightweight procedures to provide time pressure and resource drains.</p>
<p><a href="https://goblinpunch.blogspot.com/2023/04/the-underclock-fixing-random-encounter.html">The Underclock</a> is a simple way to provide random encounters at random intervals. I stripped it down to use D6&rsquo;s only and focus on the current floor, renaming it the CYBERCLOCK. It acts as a &ldquo;hurry up&rdquo; mechanic like those in arcade games &ndash; linger around and you&rsquo;ll get into trouble. You can expect a random encounter once every four times the CYBERCLOCK ticks down. On average, you can explore 12 rooms before a &ldquo;boss&rdquo; shows up, and since a floor has up to 9 rooms, that should provide enough time to explore and move on. Of course, the clock also ticks down when you cause chaos&hellip;</p>
<p>I get extra use out of the encounter table to populate rooms with extra weirdos. I even have a two-line reaction roll in there.</p>
<p>There&rsquo;s a simple resource drainer when you move between floors to incentivize players to search every room, and maybe make a tough decision or two. There are two new resources, TOKENS (a currency, for dealing with Daemons) and PARITY BITS (for moving between floors). The floor transmission procedure drains PARITY BITS or other resources on low rolls, higher rolls lower the CYBERCLOCK to give you less time to explore.</p>

    <aside class="admonition tip">
        <div class="admonition-title">
            <div class="icon"><svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" width="24" height="24" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" stroke="currentColor"
      stroke-width="2" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round" class="feather feather-sun">
      <circle cx="12" cy="12" r="5"></circle>
      <line x1="12" y1="1" x2="12" y2="3"></line>
      <line x1="12" y1="21" x2="12" y2="23"></line>
      <line x1="4.22" y1="4.22" x2="5.64" y2="5.64"></line>
      <line x1="18.36" y1="18.36" x2="19.78" y2="19.78"></line>
      <line x1="1" y1="12" x2="3" y2="12"></line>
      <line x1="21" y1="12" x2="23" y2="12"></line>
      <line x1="4.22" y1="19.78" x2="5.64" y2="18.36"></line>
      <line x1="18.36" y1="5.64" x2="19.78" y2="4.22"></line>
   </svg></div>Designing for WAR DICE</div>
        <div class="admonition-content"><p>These procedures all use a single D6 with higher results favoring FIST, so players can get maximum value from using a WAR DIE on the roll. WAR DICE are consumable D6&rsquo;s each operative has that may be added to <em>any</em> roll. Referees could inform players of this.</p>
<p>In general, I recommend designing new procedures for <em>FIST</em> like the CHOKE score: roll a D6, higher values are &ldquo;better&rdquo; or at least funnier.</p>
</div>
    </aside>
<h2 id="layout-experiments">Layout experiments</h2>
<p>I tried to do as much as I could with just text and typography, and the built-in features of Typst. Partly because I&rsquo;m lazy, but also to focus me on one tool at a time. So, this project has lots of lists and tables in various formats, trying to be eye-catching and pleasing without being distracting. I also took some hints from the <em>FIST</em> book, notably the black bars for section headings.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;m really happy with the dungeon generator spread. I&rsquo;m also pleased with the light gray accent panels and sections. The other side is kinda whatever. I like the logo, I had a lot of fun making it.</p>
<p>Funny gradient is a placeholder that never got replaced. I wanted to warp some Unix source code around it, like <em>The Matrix</em> but a lot dorkier. I also wanted to hack up some graphics of what the Ideaspace looks like (what if <em>Return of the Obra Dinn</em> had <em>four colors</em> and a polygon budget in the dozens) and what the Daemons look like (they&rsquo;re literally just the little imp dudes from <em>Zero Punctuation</em>) but that was also out of scope.</p>
<h1 id="source-code-discussion">Source code discussion</h1>
<p>I wrote this with <a href="https://typst.app">Typst</a>! This was a big step up from my earlier projects. My initial idea was to create an ARPANET pointcrawl, then remembered I don&rsquo;t know how to make adventures or pointcrawls and scaled back my plans. I was strongly inspired by <a href="https://github.com/dodgepong/typst-ha-corvette-job/">dodgepong&rsquo;s Typst conversion of the HA Corvette Job</a> and <a href="https://claymorerpgs.itch.io/rations-collection">CLAYMORE&rsquo;s RATIONS collection</a> &ndash; a trifold pamphlet seemed perfect for a jam. Two pages, six panels. A bit of hacking and I was ready to actually write the thing, directly into the layout.</p>
<h2 id="font-choice">Font choice</h2>
<p><a href="https://practicaltypography.com/charter.html">Charter</a> for body text with that 80&rsquo;s corpo document feel. It holds up great on low DPI devices, like screens or consumer printers. This is anachronistic to the late 70&rsquo;s setting of this module, but I really like Charter. Let&rsquo;s say it was created earlier than its publication but its existence was suppressed by CYCLOPS.</p>
<p><a href="https://github.com/Omnibus-Type/Archivo">Archivo</a> for headings and the encounter table numbering, for a late 20th century feel. Archivo Expanded turned out to be a decent substitute for <em>FIST</em>&rsquo;s Microgramma branding font at smaller point sizes, compared to common alternatives like <a href="https://www.theleagueofmoveabletype.com/orbitron">Orbitron</a>.</p>
<p><a href="https://tug.org/FontCatalogue/cmrfonts.html">Computer Modern Roman Dunhill</a> for the logo. This is a pretty striking font, an artistic alternative to the classic Computer Modern that triggers LaTeX flashbacks in some readers. The logo <a href="https://github.com/WindowDump/typst-ttrpg/blob/main/disks-n-daemons/template.typ#L22-L24">breaks the text into individual glpyhs</a> and places boxes around each glyph for a &ldquo;deconstructed&rdquo; appearance.</p>
<h2 id="project-structure">Project structure</h2>
<p>To separate content and presentation, there&rsquo;s a <a href="https://github.com/WindowDump/typst-ttrpg/blob/main/disks-n-daemons/template.typ">template file</a> and a <a href="https://github.com/WindowDump/typst-ttrpg/blob/main/disks-n-daemons/pamphlet.typ">main content file</a>. A trifold pamphlet is 6 panels - each of the panels is a content object. The main file is set up for screen viewing while I hack on it. For the <a href="https://github.com/WindowDump/typst-ttrpg/blob/main/disks-n-daemons/pamphlet-print.typ">print</a> and <a href="https://github.com/WindowDump/typst-ttrpg/blob/main/disks-n-daemons/pamphlet-singles.typ">singles</a> versions, I import the main file and place the panels in the desired order, or on separate pages.</p>
<h2 id="dice-generator">Dice generator</h2>
<p>I wanted to use <a href="https://speakthesky.itch.io/typeface-dicier">Dicier</a> but I noticed its shortcomings at multiple point sizes (<em>the lines keep changing thickness!</em>), so I slapped together my own <a href="https://github.com/WindowDump/typst-ttrpg/blob/main/disks-n-daemons/template.typ#L26">dice generator function</a>. This gives me full control over the stroke width, corner rounding, and background fill color without resorting to desperate hacks. It also lets me easily indicate if a die should be rotated (leading digit is odd), or if it should be an inverted color (leading digit is 2 or more). I&rsquo;m proud of the inline dice which are the same size as the text, allowing me to reference certain sides easily in little tables throughout the text.</p>
<h2 id="rounded-corner-inner-radius">Rounded corner inner radius</h2>
<p>Typst support rounding corners on blocks and rectangles. <em>FIST</em> uses rounded corners in some areas too, so I decided to have some fun with it. Making everything be a rounded blob is kinda 90&rsquo;s, and squircles are more 10&rsquo;s, but I thought it looked neat.</p>
<p>Nesting rounded corners gives us a pleasing rounded border. The formula for calculating the inner radius is <code>inner radius = outer radius - thickness</code>. This works in all units (I used points). The formula&rsquo;s floating around the internet, <a href="https://border-radius.bechbox.com">here&rsquo;s an interactive example</a>.</p>
<h1 id="whats-next">What&rsquo;s next?</h1>
<p>I hacked on a revision 2 by writing this blog post, with an eye for cleaning up the text. A few months distance and now I see all the clunky phrasing, weird structure, etc.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;d like to expand this out into a bigger version that has some art, examples of generation, room variations, maybe boxed text, who knows! The next pamphlet I make should be a bit less high-concept so it can actually fit.</p>
<h2 id="anti-canon-notes">Anti-canon notes</h2>
<p>The pseudonym <em>JRH</em> is an reference to <a href="https://www.catb.org/jargon/html/appendixb.html">J. Random Hacker</a>, or &ldquo;some random hacker that is in the way and annoying me.&rdquo;</p>
<p>There is no city or country cited for Cambridge &ndash; choose your favorite higher learning institution from any of them.</p>
<p>Thanks to bea from CLAYMORE for mentioning the PSP game <em>Coded Arms</em>, which I stole the term &ldquo;Achiba Syndrome&rdquo; from.</p>
<p>I yoinked the name &ldquo;Ideaspace&rdquo; from <em>Shin Megami Tensei: NINE</em> &ndash; it&rsquo;s the VR environment created for people to live in after Tokyo is nuked in <em>Shin Megami Tensei</em>.</p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Longshot City Character Sheet</title>
			<link>https://windowdump.github.io/posts/longshot-city-character-sheet/</link>
			<pubDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2025 16:47:32 -0400</pubDate>
			
			<guid>https://windowdump.github.io/posts/longshot-city-character-sheet/</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[Character sheet and quick reference sheet for Longshot City, the superhero TTRPG built on Troika!.]]></description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[
<figure class="webp" ><picture>
          <source srcset="/images/longshot-city-character-sheet_hu8a4bbb3ec58474e28a9e8e396f0dff72_92102_1349x1044_fit_q75_h2_box_3.webp" type="image/webp">
          <source srcset="/images/longshot-city-character-sheet_hu8a4bbb3ec58474e28a9e8e396f0dff72_92102_1349x1044_fit_q75_bgffffff_box_3.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
          <img src="/images/longshot-city-character-sheet_hu8a4bbb3ec58474e28a9e8e396f0dff72_92102_1349x1044_fit_q75_h2_box_3.webp"alt="Longshot City character sheet"  width="1349"  height="1044"  loading="lazy" />
        </picture></figure>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/WindowDump/typst-ttrpg/blob/main/orbital-blues-char-print-friendly.pdf">Longshot City character sheet and quick reference - PDF</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/WindowDump/typst-ttrpg/blob/main/longshot-city.typ">Source code (Typst)</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Link to <a href="https://melsonian-arts-council.itch.io/longshot-city">Longshot City</a>.</p>
<p>The one time I ran this game I had a time-traveling ghost possess an influencer live-streaming a self-replicating robot outbreak so they could use their psychic powers.</p>
<h1 id="source-code-discussion">Source code discussion</h1>
<p>This is the first horizontal full-page character sheet I made. I used <a href="https://typst.app">Typst</a>.</p>
<h2 id="font-choice">Font choice</h2>
<p>I went with the <a href="https://fonts.google.com/specimen/Patrick+Hand+SC">Patrick Hand SC</a> font as an easy option for a handwritten font. Kinda like comics. For numbers I used <a href="https://www.behance.net/gallery/86895479/Comic-Helvetic-(Lat-Cyr)">Comic Helvetic</a>, a blursed cross between Comic Sans and Helvetica. Tables use <a href="https://github.com/huertatipografica/Alegreya">Alegreya</a>.</p>
<h2 id="fun-with-layout">Fun with layout</h2>
<p>I started with a loose facsimile of the official sheet, with the grid evenly split down the center. After a while, I remembered I didn&rsquo;t need to fold the sheet or cut it in half, so I messed around with the grid&rsquo;s column widths, expressed as fractional units (<code>fr</code>). Typst made it easy to adjust the weights. This let me give the skills &amp; powers list and attacks list more room to breathe.</p>
<h2 id="content-from-ranges">Content from ranges</h2>
<p>In the <a href="content/posts/runic-magic.md">Runic Magic</a> project, I used <code>array.map</code> to create content from an array of dictionaries. For this project, I use a <code>for</code> loop over a <code>range()</code>. This lets me easily work with numbered content, such as the labels on the Attacks and Inventory sections of the sheet.</p>
<p>Each iteration of the loop returns a 1-length <code>array</code>, which Typst combines into a single array that I then spread to populate the containing grid.</p>

    <aside class="admonition warning">
        <div class="admonition-title">
            <div class="icon"><svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" width="24" height="24" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" stroke="currentColor"
      stroke-width="2" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round" class="feather feather-alert-circle">
      <circle cx="12" cy="12" r="10"></circle>
      <line x1="12" y1="8" x2="12" y2="12"></line>
      <line x1="12" y1="16" x2="12.01" y2="16"></line>
   </svg></div>Combined content</div>
        <div class="admonition-content"><p>If your loop returns <code>content</code>, it will all be merged into a single <code>content</code> object:</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" class="chroma"><code class="language-javascript" data-lang="javascript"><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="nx">grid</span><span class="p">(</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl">  <span class="nx">columns</span><span class="o">:</span> <span class="mi">7</span><span class="p">,</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl">  <span class="k">for</span> <span class="nx">x</span> <span class="k">in</span> <span class="nx">range</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="mi">1</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="mi">7</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl">    <span class="nx">str</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">x</span><span class="p">)</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl">  <span class="p">},</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="p">)</span>
</span></span></code></pre></div><p>This loop produces a single <code>content</code> object: <code>[123456]</code>.</p>
</div>
    </aside>

    <aside class="admonition tip">
        <div class="admonition-title">
            <div class="icon"><svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" width="24" height="24" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" stroke="currentColor"
      stroke-width="2" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round" class="feather feather-sun">
      <circle cx="12" cy="12" r="5"></circle>
      <line x1="12" y1="1" x2="12" y2="3"></line>
      <line x1="12" y1="21" x2="12" y2="23"></line>
      <line x1="4.22" y1="4.22" x2="5.64" y2="5.64"></line>
      <line x1="18.36" y1="18.36" x2="19.78" y2="19.78"></line>
      <line x1="1" y1="12" x2="3" y2="12"></line>
      <line x1="21" y1="12" x2="23" y2="12"></line>
      <line x1="4.22" y1="19.78" x2="5.64" y2="18.36"></line>
      <line x1="18.36" y1="5.64" x2="19.78" y2="4.22"></line>
   </svg></div>Spreading a for loop</div>
        <div class="admonition-content"><p>Return a 1-length array to have the loop merge them all into a single array:</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" class="chroma"><code class="language-javascript" data-lang="javascript"><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="nx">grid</span><span class="p">(</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl">  <span class="nx">columns</span><span class="o">:</span> <span class="mi">7</span><span class="p">,</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl">  <span class="p">..</span><span class="k">for</span> <span class="nx">x</span> <span class="k">in</span> <span class="nx">range</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="mi">1</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="mi">7</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl">    <span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">str</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">x</span><span class="p">),)</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl">  <span class="p">},</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="p">)</span>
</span></span></code></pre></div><p>Spreading the loop places 6 items in the <code>grid</code>: <code>[1], [2], [3], [4], [5], [6]</code>.</p>
</div>
    </aside>
<p>I didn&rsquo;t realize you could use the <code>*</code> operator to make copies of content, so there&rsquo;s a few spots where I use this method even though I don&rsquo;t need to do anything with the number.</p>
<h2 id="quick-reference-sheet">Quick reference sheet</h2>
<p>An exercise in information density. <em>Longshot City</em> uses per-weapon lookup tables for damage, which you copy onto your character sheet (in theory). Power stamina also aren&rsquo;t noted in the character backgrounds section, and it&rsquo;s inconvenient to flip through the book to find them. It&rsquo;s also easier if there&rsquo;s a sheet everyone can pass around instead of the one device with the PDF.</p>

<figure class="webp" ><picture>
          <source srcset="/images/longshot-city-quick-reference_hu7ca8f0ca4b157bb21a41ff6db8c085f4_511366_1349x1044_fit_q75_h2_box_3.webp" type="image/webp">
          <source srcset="/images/longshot-city-quick-reference_hu7ca8f0ca4b157bb21a41ff6db8c085f4_511366_1349x1044_fit_q75_bgffffff_box_3.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
          <img src="/images/longshot-city-quick-reference_hu7ca8f0ca4b157bb21a41ff6db8c085f4_511366_1349x1044_fit_q75_h2_box_3.webp"alt="Longshot City character sheet"  width="1349"  height="1044"  loading="lazy" />
        </picture></figure>
<p>Nothing tricky for these, just raw brute force. I store the actual table contents in arrays to make them easier to handle &ndash; they&rsquo;re quite long when the code formatter forces each number onto its own line, just your standard comma separated values.</p>
<p>I need to do another editing pass or two on the rules reference &ndash; probably rip out the entire initiative section (&ldquo;let the GM tell you when it&rsquo;s your turn, each combat round is one two-page spread long&rdquo;) to make room for more examples.</p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Runic Magic</title>
			<link>https://windowdump.github.io/posts/runic-magic/</link>
			<pubDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2025 16:36:39 -0400</pubDate>
			
			<guid>https://windowdump.github.io/posts/runic-magic/</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[A set of runes on printable cards, kinda like Ultima, with suggested rules for fantasy TTRPGS (and FIST).]]></description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[
<figure class="webp" ><picture>
          <source srcset="/images/runic-magic_hu5e59f8b9a2dbbaddd0b1f77fc9784710_117412_1248x943_fit_q75_h2_box_3.webp" type="image/webp">
          <source srcset="/images/runic-magic_hu5e59f8b9a2dbbaddd0b1f77fc9784710_117412_1248x943_fit_q75_bgffffff_box_3.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
          <img src="/images/runic-magic_hu5e59f8b9a2dbbaddd0b1f77fc9784710_117412_1248x943_fit_q75_h2_box_3.webp"alt="Runic Magic preview"  width="1248"  height="943"  loading="lazy" />
        </picture></figure>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/WindowDump/typst-ttrpg/blob/main/runic-magic.pdf">Runic Magic - PDF</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/WindowDump/typst-ttrpg/blob/main/runic-magic.typ">Source code (Typst)</a></li>
</ul>
<p><a href="https://typst.app/project/rGATRmPoeLmBhpPKvWCDni">Original text by skander.</a> Shout out to <a href="https://amag111.itch.io">skander&rsquo;s itch</a>, get <a href="https://amag111.itch.io/runic-magic-for-ttrpgs">his version of this document</a> to double your runes.</p>
<p>Lightweight interpretive magic system. Uses the <a href="https://wiki.ultimacodex.com/wiki/Incantation">Runes</a> from the classic <em>Ultima</em> CRPG series. These are the building blocks of <a href="https://wiki.ultimacodex.com/wiki/Britannian_magic">Britiannian magic</a>: each spell is made of one or more runes, and casting them in some games requires you to type in the runes for the spell every time you cast it.</p>
<p>Spells are legally-distinct <em>D&amp;D</em> types, as was the style at the time. The runes to cast them are thematic, with more powerful spells requiring multiple runes. For a few examples, Light is <em><code>In Lor</code></em> &ndash; &ldquo;create light&rdquo;, Fireball is <em><code>Vas Flam Hur</code></em> &ndash; &ldquo;great flame wind&rdquo;, and Resurrect is <em><code>In Mani Corp</code></em> &ndash; &ldquo;create life death.&rdquo; Poke around the <a href="https://wiki.ultimacodex.com/wiki/Category:Ultima_VII_spells">Ultima VII spell list</a> for more.</p>
<p>Because I could fit it, this document has instructions on how to use it as a <a href="https://claymorerpgs.itch.io/fist">FIST</a> trait. For completeness&hellip;</p>
<h2 id="runic-magic">RUNIC MAGIC</h2>
<p>You are a practitioner of a magical art that uses runes as its fundamental unit. These 24 runes can be represented as cards on <a href="https://github.com/WindowDump/typst-ttrpg/blob/main/runic-magic.pdf">the second page of this document</a>. Assemble them into a deck (allows for repeated random drawing with no duplicates).</p>
<p>When you have time for meditation and connection with the sources of your power, such as between missions or at certain rendezvous points, return all your runes to the deck, shuffle, and draw <strong>2D6 + your number of traits</strong> runes. Once used, a rune loses power until you draw runes.</p>
<p>To cast a spell, choose one or more runes to form the basis of a reasonable spell. Casting a spell is always <em>risky</em>, roll <strong>2D6 + modifiers</strong> (see below) like other risky actions to see if there is a complication or if the spell turns out badly.</p>
<p>By default, a spell takes 30-60 seconds to cast, lasts for a single use or with active concentration, and affects you or someone you touch in a noticeable way.</p>
<ul>
<li>Add <strong>+ 1</strong> to the roll for each:
<ul>
<li>Use more than 2 runes in the spell</li>
<li>Sacrifice 1D6 HP</li>
<li>Take much longer</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Subtract <strong>- 1</strong> from the roll for each:
<ul>
<li>Increase range</li>
<li>Affect group or area</li>
<li>Cast instantly</li>
<li>Subtle effect and casting</li>
<li>Long-lasting</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Trait item: a bag of 24 runes<br>
Trait bonus: +1 MAX HP</p>

    <aside class="admonition warning">
        <div class="admonition-title">
            <div class="icon"><svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" width="24" height="24" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" stroke="currentColor"
      stroke-width="2" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round" class="feather feather-alert-circle">
      <circle cx="12" cy="12" r="10"></circle>
      <line x1="12" y1="8" x2="12" y2="12"></line>
      <line x1="12" y1="16" x2="12.01" y2="16"></line>
   </svg></div>Referee Note</div>
        <div class="admonition-content">I did not playtest the number of runes drawn, have fun!</div>
    </aside>
<h1 id="source-code-discussion">Source code discussion</h1>
<p>This was written in <a href="https://typst.app">Typst</a>, and I learned a few tricks while making this. In fact, I made this because I got inspired to try out these tricks.</p>
<h2 id="font-choice">Font choice</h2>
<p><a href="https://psb1558.github.io/Elstob-font/">Elstob</a>, for that medievalist feeling. It supports runic glyphs via stylistic alternatives, which you can access with CSS.</p>
<h2 id="content-organization">Content organization</h2>
<p>Runes are stored as an array of dictionaries:</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" class="chroma"><code class="language-javascript" data-lang="javascript"><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="kd">let</span> <span class="nx">runes</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="p">(</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl">  <span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">glyph</span><span class="o">:</span> <span class="s2">&#34;ᚫ&#34;</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="nx">name</span><span class="o">:</span> <span class="s2">&#34;An&#34;</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="nx">meaning</span><span class="o">:</span> <span class="s2">&#34;Negate&#34;</span><span class="p">),</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl">  <span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">glyph</span><span class="o">:</span> <span class="s2">&#34;ᛒ&#34;</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="nx">name</span><span class="o">:</span> <span class="s2">&#34;Bet&#34;</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="nx">meaning</span><span class="o">:</span> <span class="s2">&#34;Small&#34;</span><span class="p">),</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl">  <span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">glyph</span><span class="o">:</span> <span class="s2">&#34;ᚳ&#34;</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="nx">name</span><span class="o">:</span> <span class="s2">&#34;Corp&#34;</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="nx">meaning</span><span class="o">:</span> <span class="s2">&#34;Death&#34;</span><span class="p">),</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl">  <span class="p">...</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="p">)</span>
</span></span></code></pre></div><p>This lets you separate content and its presentation (very web 2.0). I took advantage of this to create two different grids, one for reference (on the first page), one for printing (on the second page).</p>
<h2 id="building-the-grid">Building the grid</h2>
<p>With the <code>runes</code> array, we use the <a href="https://typst.app/docs/reference/foundations/array/#definitions-map"><code>array.map</code></a> method to transform the dictionaries into content, in this case <code>grid</code>&rsquo;s. Because <code>map</code> return an array, we need to spread it to pass the content into a containing <code>grid</code>.</p>

    <aside class="admonition failure">
        <div class="admonition-title">
            <div class="icon"><svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" width="24" height="24" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" stroke="currentColor"
      stroke-width="2" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round" class="feather feather-x-circle">
      <circle cx="12" cy="12" r="10"></circle>
      <line x1="15" y1="9" x2="9" y2="15"></line>
      <line x1="9" y1="9" x2="15" y2="15"></line>
   </svg></div>Expected content, found array.</div>
        <div class="admonition-content"><p>Many functions like <code>grid</code> expect <code>content</code> (one or multiple instances). Passing an array to them results in an error:</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" class="chroma"><code class="language-javascript" data-lang="javascript"><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="nx">grid</span><span class="p">(</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl">  <span class="nx">columns</span><span class="o">:</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="mi">1</span><span class="nx">fr</span><span class="p">,)</span> <span class="o">*</span> <span class="mi">6</span><span class="p">,</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl">  <span class="nx">runes</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">map</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">rune</span> <span class="p">=&gt;</span> <span class="nx">grid</span><span class="p">(</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl">    <span class="nx">rune</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">name</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="nx">rune</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">glyph</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="nx">rune</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">meaning</span><span class="p">,</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl">  <span class="p">)),</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="p">)</span>
</span></span></code></pre></div></div>
    </aside>

    <aside class="admonition success">
        <div class="admonition-title">
            <div class="icon"><svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" width="24" height="24" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" stroke="currentColor"
      stroke-width="2" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round" class="feather feather-check-circle">
      <path d="M22 11.08V12a10 10 0 1 1-5.93-9.14"></path>
      <polyline points="22 4 12 14.01 9 11.01"></polyline>
   </svg></div>Spread the array!</div>
        <div class="admonition-content"><p>The <code>..</code> spread operator returns the contents of the array, our desired <code>content</code>:</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" class="chroma"><code class="language-javascript" data-lang="javascript"><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="nx">grid</span><span class="p">(</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl">  <span class="nx">columns</span><span class="o">:</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="mi">1</span><span class="nx">fr</span><span class="p">,)</span> <span class="o">*</span> <span class="mi">6</span><span class="p">,</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl">  <span class="p">..</span><span class="nx">runes</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">map</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">rune</span> <span class="p">=&gt;</span> <span class="nx">grid</span><span class="p">(</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl">    <span class="nx">rune</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">name</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="nx">rune</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">glyph</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="nx">rune</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">meaning</span><span class="p">,</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl">  <span class="p">)),</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="p">)</span>
</span></span></code></pre></div></div>
    </aside>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>WoDu Remix Character Sheet</title>
			<link>https://windowdump.github.io/posts/wodu-remix-character-sheet/</link>
			<pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2024 12:57:47 -0400</pubDate>
			
			<guid>https://windowdump.github.io/posts/wodu-remix-character-sheet/</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[A half-letter character sheet for (World of Dungeons / WoDu) Remix, in various styles.]]></description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[
<figure class="webp" ><picture>
          <source srcset="/images/wodu-remix-sheet-halfletter-flare_huc8a94e1ef92101a27bcbdc4167bd8e7f_366276_1860x1426_fit_q75_h2_box_3.webp" type="image/webp">
          <source srcset="/images/wodu-remix-sheet-halfletter-flare_huc8a94e1ef92101a27bcbdc4167bd8e7f_366276_1860x1426_fit_q75_bgffffff_box_3.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
          <img src="/images/wodu-remix-sheet-halfletter-flare_huc8a94e1ef92101a27bcbdc4167bd8e7f_366276_1860x1426_fit_q75_h2_box_3.webp"alt="WoDu Remix half-letter character sheet, Flare gradient"  width="1860"  height="1426"  loading="lazy" />
        </picture><figcaption>
            <p><code>flare</code> gradient version</p>
          </figcaption></figure>
<ul>
<li><a href="../../stuff/wodu-remix-sheet-halfletter-bw.pdf">Black &amp; White - PDF</a></li>
<li><a href="../../stuff/wodu-remix-sheet-halfletter-lowink.pdf">Low Ink, Single Contrast - PDF</a></li>
<li><a href="../../stuff/wodu-remix-sheet-halfletter-flare.pdf">flare, color - PDF</a></li>
<li><a href="../../stuff/fist-operative-handbook.typ">Source Code (Typst)</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Branching off from <em>FIST</em>, I found the neat <a href="https://itch.io/c/3165867/pbta-osr-synthesis">PbtA + OSR collection on Itch</a> that contains a bunch of games inspired by <a href="https://johnharper.itch.io/world-of-dungeons">World of Dungeons</a> (<em>WoDu</em><sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup>), the <em>Dungeon World</em> pre-order bonus that&rsquo;s basically <em>B/X D&amp;D</em> but you do the 2d6 thing from <em>Apocalypse World</em> instead of a d20. Among the collection is <a href="https://katamoiran.itch.io/remix">Remix</a> (<em>WoDu Remix</em>) which neatly splits the difference between the OSR, storygames, and <em>5e</em>, and makes me excited every time I crack it open.</p>
<p>After finishing up the <em>FIST</em> character sheet and understanding the basics of <a href="https://typst.app/">Typst</a>, I decided to try a <em>WoDu Remix</em> sheet since the two games are similar. Taking the original <em>WoDu</em> sheet as inspiration, I added the new skill list, provided more room for special abilities, and included the extra stats and fields (heritage, bonus damage, first aid, debilities).</p>
<p>During the process I realized I could build a sheet out of negative space on top of a colored background, working around Typst&rsquo;s lack of masking or clipping support. This let me make some fairly striking designs with gradients on the borders. Typst comes loaded with a bunch of cool data visualization gradients (<code>flare</code> is a standout) and it&rsquo;s easy to make your own.</p>
<p>I made a few different versions of the sheet. First up is classic <em>black &amp; white</em>, which would look good out of a laser printer.</p>

<figure class="webp" ><a href="../../stuff/wodu-remix-sheet-halfletter-bw.pdf"><picture>
          <source srcset="/images/wodu-remix-sheet-halfletter-bw_hud2aa8a4e3e9d3645c6ca8d0ac2f607ba_158518_1860x1426_fit_q75_h2_box_3.webp" type="image/webp">
          <source srcset="/images/wodu-remix-sheet-halfletter-bw_hud2aa8a4e3e9d3645c6ca8d0ac2f607ba_158518_1860x1426_fit_q75_bgffffff_box_3.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
          <img src="/images/wodu-remix-sheet-halfletter-bw_hud2aa8a4e3e9d3645c6ca8d0ac2f607ba_158518_1860x1426_fit_q75_h2_box_3.webp"alt="WoDu Remix half-letter character sheet, black &amp; white"  width="1860"  height="1426"  loading="lazy" />
        </picture></a><figcaption>
            <h4><a href="../../stuff/wodu-remix-sheet-halfletter-bw.pdf">Black &amp; White - PDF</a></h4>
          </figcaption></figure>
<p>Next is a high-contrast, lower ink version. It features only black text and a <code>0.25pt</code> stroke around the small boxes players write in. This is suitable for ink-jet printers and photocopiers. You may also find it easier to read.</p>

<figure class="webp" ><a href="../../stuff/wodu-remix-sheet-halfletter-lowink.pdf"><picture>
          <source srcset="/images/wodu-remix-sheet-halfletter-lowink_hu383df2949f6c9d31d3b21649677f6ff3_168187_1860x1426_fit_q75_h2_box_3.webp" type="image/webp">
          <source srcset="/images/wodu-remix-sheet-halfletter-lowink_hu383df2949f6c9d31d3b21649677f6ff3_168187_1860x1426_fit_q75_bgffffff_box_3.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
          <img src="/images/wodu-remix-sheet-halfletter-lowink_hu383df2949f6c9d31d3b21649677f6ff3_168187_1860x1426_fit_q75_h2_box_3.webp"alt="WoDu Remix half-letter character sheet, low-ink single contrast"  width="1860"  height="1426"  loading="lazy" />
        </picture></a><figcaption>
            <h4><a href="../../stuff/wodu-remix-sheet-halfletter-lowink.pdf">Low Ink, Single Contrast - PDF</a></h4>
          </figcaption></figure>
<p>Finally, we have one with the <code>flare</code> gradient from Typst, a yellow to purple gradient that is perceptibly uniform with colors reminsicient of a sunset. I added a chrome text effect to the header text as well.</p>

<figure class="webp" ><a href="../../stuff/wodu-remix-sheet-halfletter-flare.pdf"><picture>
          <source srcset="/images/wodu-remix-sheet-halfletter-flare_huc8a94e1ef92101a27bcbdc4167bd8e7f_366276_1860x1426_fit_q75_h2_box_3.webp" type="image/webp">
          <source srcset="/images/wodu-remix-sheet-halfletter-flare_huc8a94e1ef92101a27bcbdc4167bd8e7f_366276_1860x1426_fit_q75_bgffffff_box_3.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
          <img src="/images/wodu-remix-sheet-halfletter-flare_huc8a94e1ef92101a27bcbdc4167bd8e7f_366276_1860x1426_fit_q75_h2_box_3.webp"alt="WoDu Remix half-letter character sheet, Flare gradient"  width="1860"  height="1426"  loading="lazy" />
        </picture></a><figcaption>
            <h4><a href="../../stuff/wodu-remix-sheet-halfletter-flare.pdf"><code>flare</code> gradient - PDF</a></h4>
          </figcaption></figure>
<p>It&rsquo;s easy to riff on these, if you have Typst set up download the source code and try playing with it. Try changing the color of the grid, or messing with a gradient, or applying an image or pattern, etc. You can also change the fonts if you decide Trebuchet is more your speed than Jost, for example.</p>
<p>If you want to start making your own <em>WoDu</em> hack, you could start by editing this character sheet! Change the attributes to something more flavorful, choose skills that model the world you&rsquo;re playing in, decide what stats you need, and keep going! You&rsquo;ll be ready for playtesting in no time.</p>
<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
<hr>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>That&rsquo;s <em>WoDu</em>, not <em>WoD</em> which is <em>World of Darkness</em>.&#160;<a href="#fnref:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>FIST Operative Handbook</title>
			<link>https://windowdump.github.io/posts/fist-operative-handbook/</link>
			<pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2024 12:52:47 -0400</pubDate>
			
			<guid>https://windowdump.github.io/posts/fist-operative-handbook/</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[A zine-style half-letter character sheet and rules summary for FIST, a paranormal mercenary TTRPG.]]></description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[
<figure class="webp" ><picture>
          <source srcset="/images/fist-handbook_hu7838f2a5e1a46772b1cd164ed9dd9086_301065_1269x1006_fit_q75_h2_box_3.webp" type="image/webp">
          <source srcset="/images/fist-handbook_hu7838f2a5e1a46772b1cd164ed9dd9086_301065_1269x1006_fit_q75_bgffffff_box_3.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
          <img src="/images/fist-handbook_hu7838f2a5e1a46772b1cd164ed9dd9086_301065_1269x1006_fit_q75_h2_box_3.webp"alt="FIST Operative Handbook preview"  width="1269"  height="1006"  loading="lazy" />
        </picture></figure>
<ul>
<li><a href="../../stuff/fist-operative-handbook.pdf">FIST Operative Handbook - PDF</a></li>
<li><a href="../../stuff/fist-sheet-halfletter.pdf">FIST half-letter character sheet - PDF</a></li>
<li><a href="../../stuff/fist-operative-handbook.typ">Source Code (Typst)</a></li>
</ul>
<p>I&rsquo;m a big fan of <a href="https://claymorerpgs.itch.io/fist">FIST</a>, a TTRPG about paranormal mercenaries (think <em>Metal Gear</em>) doing jobs for regular people no one else can (or no one else wants to) during the Cold War (think <em>The A-Team</em>). One of my favorite parts is how quickly a character can be generated, and how flavorful these characters are. Check out <a href="https://fistref.com/random-merc">FISTREF&rsquo;s Random Merc page</a> if you want to see it in action for yourself. FIST&rsquo;s anti-canon sandbox defines the world with the help of the characters.</p>
<p>FIST&rsquo;s core is short and concise, and I decided to combine a rules reference and a character sheet together for a zine-style booklet. This is particularly useful for new players who haven&rsquo;t read the player rules yet. You can read both sides, follow the character creation rules on the outside, then fold it in half to maximize table space.</p>
<p>This was a first project in <a href="https://typst.app/">Typst</a> so there&rsquo;s probably a lot of ugly hacks in there - I might clean it up later. Possible project for the reader: replace Orbitron and Michroma with Microgramma (aka the <em>Drake &amp; Josh</em> font), update letter-spacing as needed.</p>
<p>I also made a version that&rsquo;s just the character sheet twice, so you can print out two character sheets at once!</p>
<p>This is kind of a cool format for a one-page game that was surprisingly easy to whip up.</p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Hello World!</title>
			<link>https://windowdump.github.io/posts/my-first-post/</link>
			<pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2024 12:55:34 -0400</pubDate>
			
			<guid>https://windowdump.github.io/posts/my-first-post/</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[test post please ignore]]></description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="this-is-a-test-post">This is a test post</h2>
<p>Hello. This is a post that I might mark as a draft in the near future. It&rsquo;s a testing post that demonstrates various features of this blog and the styles defined for it. I care way too much about this stuff, but I&rsquo;m getting it out of the way so I don&rsquo;t get distracted by it later (I will get distracted by layout and formatting stuff later).</p>
<p><del>A lot of this website is me playing with <a href="https://psb1558.github.io/Elstob-font/">Elstob</a>, a font based on one used by the Oxford University Press in the 17th century. With the power of modern technology it graces your eyeballs once again, except this time with an anachronistic grade axis. It&rsquo;s an old style font, so it&rsquo;s designed for black ink on white paper, but maybe white pixels on dark pixels will be good too.</del></p>
<p>Just kidding, decided to swap over to <a href="https://github.com/adobe-fonts/source-serif">Source Serif 4</a> and <a href="https://github.com/indestructible-type/Drafting">Drafting* Mono</a>.</p>
<h3 id="hot-new-features">Hot New Features</h3>
<p>I added these because Elstob supports them. They&rsquo;re implemented as Hugo shortcodes.</p>
<ul>
<li>Insular mode
<ul>
<li>Uses insular letter shapes and caps to small caps.
<ul>
<li>
<span style="font-feature-settings: 'c2sc', 'ss02'">It&rsquo;s kinda like that movie, <em>The Lord of the Rings</em>.</span></li>
<li>source serif: c2sc works! insular doesn&rsquo;t</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Elder Futhark mode
<ul>
<li>24 Norse runes, maps to  English letters. Q is mapped to K, Y is mapped to I, X is mapped to G.
<ul>
<li>
<span style="font-feature-settings: 'ss13'">runic probabli makes more sense than english tbkh</span></li>
<li>
<span style="font-feature-settings: 'ss13'">we <em>ultima</em> now</span></li>
<li>maybe not anymore</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<span style="font-feature-settings: 'ss13'">abcdefghijklm nopkrstuvwgiz abcdefghijklm nopkrstuvwgiz</span></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Changed syntax highlighting style
<ul>
<li>Slammed <a href="https://draculatheme.com/contribute#color-palette">Dracula</a> on the site. I dunno, I dig the high contrast candy colors of that theme.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="todo">todo</h3>
<p>Here is a wishlist of things I&rsquo;d like to do in the near future:</p>
<ul>
<li>Rollable tables
<ul>
<li>Display a table along with two buttons: &ldquo;get 1&rdquo; and &ldquo;get 5&rdquo;.</li>
<li>Usable as a game aid or prep aid!
<ul>
<li>Bonus round: Use <a href="https://speakthesky.itch.io/typeface-dicier">Dicier</a> to style the table entries for D66 (36), D63 (18), or D33 (9) tables.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>I get to practice making tables.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>A large number of imperceptable changes you will never notice but I can&rsquo;t stop staring at.
<ul>
<li>I&rsquo;m a real typographer now.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Theme is based on <a href="https://1bl4z3r.github.io/hermit-V2/en/">Hermit V2</a>. I&rsquo;ve done a lot of hacking to it because I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://practicaltypography.com">Butterick&rsquo;s Practical Typography</a>.</p>
<p>Visit the <a href="https://gohugo.io">Hugo</a> website!</p>
<h1 id="level-1-testing">Level 1 testing</h1>
<p>Butterick recommends 45 to 90 characters per line. Here are lines of 26, 52, and 78 characters.</p>
<p>abcde fghij klmno pqrst uvwxyz</p>
<p>abcde fghij klmno pqrst uvwxyz abcde fghij klmno pqrst uvwxyz</p>
<p>abcde fghij klmno pqrst uvwxyz abcde fghij klmno pqrst uvwxyz abcde fghij klmno pqrst uvwxyz</p>
<p>y&rsquo;all like oldstyle numerals? 1234567890</p>
<p>Personally I have a soft spot for those suckers. We see lining numerals everywhere, every day - they&rsquo;ve been the default for so long. Same with tabular numerals. If you&rsquo;re making a chart or a table, or working with monospace fonts, tabular lining numerals are the way to go, and they&rsquo;ve become so commonplace they don&rsquo;t look odd when you see them in text. So they&rsquo;re a reasonable default. But I&rsquo;m not using the default settings! I want to go wild and so something you haven&rsquo;t seen before.</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" class="chroma"><code class="language-Python" data-lang="Python"><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="nb">print</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s2">&#34;Hello World! 1234567890&#34;</span><span class="p">)</span>
</span></span></code></pre></div><ul>
<li>Unordered List</li>
<li>Item One
<ul>
<li>Nested List</li>
<li>Still Nestin'
<ul>
<li>Revenge of the Nest</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="level-2">Level 2</h2>
<p>it&rsquo;s time to dive deep and greedily</p>
<h3 id="level-3">Level 3</h3>
<p>oooh it&rsquo;s going down!</p>
<h4 id="level-4">Level 4</h4>
<p>don&rsquo;t go any deeper</p>
<h1 id="a-longer-block-of-text">A longer block of text</h1>
<p>The rest of this page is just the <a href="https://1bl4z3r.github.io/hermit-V2/en/posts/typography/">Hermit-V2 typography page</a>.</p>
<p>Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipiscing elit, sed do eiusmod tempor incididunt ut labore et dolore magna aliqua. Ut enim ad minim veniam, quis nostrud exercitation ullamco laboris nisi ut aliquip ex ea commodo consequat. Duis aute irure dolor in reprehenderit in voluptate velit esse cillum dolore eu fugiat nulla pariatur. Excepteur sint occaecat cupidatat non proident, sunt in culpa qui officia deserunt mollit anim id est laborum.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>An apple is a sweet, edible fruit produced by an apple tree (Malus pumila). Apple trees are cultivated worldwide, and are the most widely grown species in the genus Malus. The tree originated in Central Asia, where its wild ancestor, Malus sieversii, is still found today. Apples have been grown for thousands of years in Asia and Europe, and were brought to North America by European colonists. Apples have religious and mythological significance in many cultures, including Norse, Greek and European Christian traditions.<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup></p>
</blockquote>

    <aside class="admonition tip">
        <div class="admonition-title">
            <div class="icon"><svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" width="24" height="24" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" stroke="currentColor"
      stroke-width="2" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round" class="feather feather-sun">
      <circle cx="12" cy="12" r="5"></circle>
      <line x1="12" y1="1" x2="12" y2="3"></line>
      <line x1="12" y1="21" x2="12" y2="23"></line>
      <line x1="4.22" y1="4.22" x2="5.64" y2="5.64"></line>
      <line x1="18.36" y1="18.36" x2="19.78" y2="19.78"></line>
      <line x1="1" y1="12" x2="3" y2="12"></line>
      <line x1="21" y1="12" x2="23" y2="12"></line>
      <line x1="4.22" y1="19.78" x2="5.64" y2="18.36"></line>
      <line x1="18.36" y1="5.64" x2="19.78" y2="4.22"></line>
   </svg></div>Pro Tip</div>
        <div class="admonition-content">Shoot the Cyberdemon with rockets until it dies.</div>
    </aside>

    <aside class="admonition failure">
        <div class="admonition-title">
            <div class="icon"><svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" width="24" height="24" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" stroke="currentColor"
      stroke-width="2" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round" class="feather feather-x-circle">
      <circle cx="12" cy="12" r="10"></circle>
      <line x1="15" y1="9" x2="9" y2="15"></line>
      <line x1="9" y1="9" x2="15" y2="15"></line>
   </svg></div>Skill issues</div>
        <div class="admonition-content">Don&rsquo;t walk into the Cyberdemon&rsquo;s rockets or you&rsquo;ll die.</div>
    </aside>
<hr>
<p>Inline styles：</p>
<p><strong>strong</strong>, <em>emphasis</em>, <em><strong>strong and emphasis</strong></em>,<code>code</code>, <del>strikethrough</del>, &#x1f602;🤣, $\LaTeX$<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">2</a></sup>, ==highlight==, <a href="https://example.com">Link</a>, and image:</p>
<p><img src="https://picsum.photos/600/400/?random" alt="img"></p>
<p>Images can also be implemented via figure shortcode. It extends in-built hugo shortcode to convert images to webp format.</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" class="chroma"><code class="language-go" data-lang="go"><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="p">{</span> <span class="p">{&lt;</span> <span class="nx">figure</span> <span class="nx">src</span><span class="p">=</span><span class="s">&#34;images/wodu-remix-sheet-halfletter-flare.png&#34;</span> <span class="nx">title</span><span class="p">=</span><span class="s">&#34;WoDu Character Sheet, flare version&#34;</span> <span class="nx">alt</span><span class="p">=</span><span class="s">&#34;A WEBP converted image&#34;</span> <span class="nx">caption</span><span class="p">=</span><span class="s">&#34;A WEBP converted image&#34;</span> <span class="nx">class</span><span class="p">=</span><span class="s">&#34;webp&#34;</span> <span class="nx">loading</span><span class="p">=</span><span class="s">&#34;lazy&#34;</span> <span class="p">&gt;}</span> <span class="p">}</span>
</span></span></code></pre></div>
<figure class="webp" ><picture>
          <source srcset="/images/wodu-remix-sheet-halfletter-flare_huc8a94e1ef92101a27bcbdc4167bd8e7f_366276_1860x1426_fit_q75_h2_box_3.webp" type="image/webp">
          <source srcset="/images/wodu-remix-sheet-halfletter-flare_huc8a94e1ef92101a27bcbdc4167bd8e7f_366276_1860x1426_fit_q75_bgffffff_box_3.jpg" type="image/jpeg">
          <img src="/images/wodu-remix-sheet-halfletter-flare_huc8a94e1ef92101a27bcbdc4167bd8e7f_366276_1860x1426_fit_q75_h2_box_3.webp"alt="A WEBP converted image"  width="1860"  height="1426"  loading="lazy" />
        </picture><figcaption>
            <h4>WoDu Character Sheet, flare version</h4><p>A WEBP converted image</p>
          </figcaption></figure>
<p>Yes, and now here&rsquo;s some more stuff after the figure.</p>
<hr>
<p>Headings:</p>
<h1 id="typography-testing">Typography Testing</h1>
<p>Table:</p>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th style="text-align:left">Left-Aligned</th>
<th style="text-align:center">Center Aligned</th>
<th style="text-align:right">Right Aligned</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:left">col 3 is</td>
<td style="text-align:center">some wordy text</td>
<td style="text-align:right">$1600</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:left">col 2 is</td>
<td style="text-align:center">centered</td>
<td style="text-align:right">$12</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:left">zebra stripes</td>
<td style="text-align:center">are neat</td>
<td style="text-align:right">$1</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>Lists:</p>
<ul>
<li>Unordered list item 1.</li>
<li>Unordered list item 2.</li>
</ul>
<ol>
<li>ordered list item 1.</li>
<li>ordered list item 2.
<ul>
<li>sub-unordered list item 1.</li>
<li>sub-unordered list item 2.
<ul>
<li><input checked="" disabled="" type="checkbox"> something is DONE.</li>
<li><input disabled="" type="checkbox"> something is NOT DONE.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ol>
<p>Syntax Highlighting without backticks:</p>
<pre><code>dt = {5:4, 1:6, 6:3}
sorted_dt = {key: value for key, value in sorted(dt.items(), key=lambda item: item[1])}
print(sorted_dt)
</code></pre>
<p>Syntax Highlighting with backticks:</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" class="chroma"><code class="language-javascript" data-lang="javascript"><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="kd">var</span> <span class="nx">num1</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="nx">num2</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="nx">sum</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="nx">num1</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="nx">prompt</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s2">&#34;Enter first number&#34;</span><span class="p">)</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="nx">num2</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="nx">prompt</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s2">&#34;Enter second number&#34;</span><span class="p">)</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="nx">sum</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="nb">parseInt</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">num1</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="o">+</span> <span class="nb">parseInt</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">num2</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="c1">// &#34;+&#34; means &#34;add&#34;
</span></span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="c1"></span><span class="nx">alert</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s2">&#34;Sum = &#34;</span> <span class="o">+</span> <span class="nx">sum</span><span class="p">)</span>  <span class="c1">// &#34;+&#34; means combine into a string
</span></span></span></code></pre></div><p>Syntax Highlighting with <a href="https://gohugo.io/content-management/syntax-highlighting/"><code>highlight</code> shortcode</a></p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" class="chroma"><code class="language-go" data-lang="go"><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="p">{{</span><span class="cm">/*&lt; highlight css &#34;linenos=table,linenostart=5&#34; &gt;*/</span><span class="p">}}</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="cm">/* LineHighlight */</span> <span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">chroma</span> <span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">hl</span> <span class="p">{</span> <span class="nx">display</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="nx">block</span><span class="p">;</span> <span class="nx">width</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="mi">100</span><span class="o">%</span><span class="p">;</span><span class="nx">background</span><span class="o">-</span><span class="nx">color</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="err">#</span><span class="mi">55595</span><span class="nx">ebb</span> <span class="p">}</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="p">{{</span><span class="cm">/*&lt; /highlight &gt;*/</span><span class="p">}}</span>
</span></span></code></pre></div><div class="highlight"><div class="chroma">
<table class="lntable"><tr><td class="lntd">
<pre tabindex="0" class="chroma"><code><span class="lnt">5
</span></code></pre></td>
<td class="lntd">
<pre tabindex="0" class="chroma"><code class="language-css" data-lang="css"><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="c">/* LineHighlight */</span> <span class="p">.</span><span class="nc">chroma</span> <span class="p">.</span><span class="nc">hl</span> <span class="p">{</span> <span class="k">display</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="kc">block</span><span class="p">;</span> <span class="k">width</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="mi">100</span><span class="kt">%</span><span class="p">;</span><span class="k">background-color</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="mh">#55595e</span><span class="n">bb</span> <span class="p">}</span></span></span></code></pre></td></tr></table>
</div>
</div>
<p>Change Highlight color in <code>_syntax.scss</code> Line 5</p>
<div class="highlight"><div class="chroma">
<table class="lntable"><tr><td class="lntd">
<pre tabindex="0" class="chroma"><code><span class="lnt"> 1
</span><span class="lnt"> 2
</span><span class="lnt"> 3
</span><span class="lnt"> 4
</span><span class="hl"><span class="lnt"> 5
</span></span><span class="lnt"> 6
</span><span class="lnt"> 7
</span><span class="lnt"> 8
</span><span class="lnt"> 9
</span><span class="lnt">10
</span><span class="lnt">11
</span><span class="lnt">12
</span><span class="lnt">13
</span><span class="lnt">14
</span><span class="lnt">15
</span><span class="lnt">16
</span><span class="lnt">17
</span><span class="lnt">18
</span><span class="lnt">19
</span><span class="lnt">20
</span><span class="lnt">21
</span><span class="lnt">22
</span><span class="hl"><span class="lnt">23
</span></span><span class="hl"><span class="lnt">24
</span></span><span class="hl"><span class="lnt">25
</span></span><span class="hl"><span class="lnt">26
</span></span><span class="hl"><span class="lnt">27
</span></span><span class="hl"><span class="lnt">28
</span></span><span class="hl"><span class="lnt">29
</span></span><span class="hl"><span class="lnt">30
</span></span><span class="hl"><span class="lnt">31
</span></span><span class="hl"><span class="lnt">32
</span></span><span class="hl"><span class="lnt">33
</span></span><span class="lnt">34
</span><span class="lnt">35
</span><span class="lnt">36
</span><span class="lnt">37
</span><span class="lnt">38
</span><span class="lnt">39
</span><span class="lnt">40
</span><span class="lnt">41
</span><span class="lnt">42
</span><span class="lnt">43
</span><span class="lnt">44
</span><span class="lnt">45
</span><span class="lnt">46
</span><span class="lnt">47
</span><span class="lnt">48
</span><span class="lnt">49
</span><span class="lnt">50
</span><span class="lnt">51
</span><span class="lnt">52
</span><span class="lnt">53
</span><span class="lnt">54
</span><span class="lnt">55
</span><span class="lnt">56
</span><span class="lnt">57
</span><span class="lnt">58
</span><span class="lnt">59
</span><span class="lnt">60
</span><span class="lnt">61
</span><span class="lnt">62
</span><span class="lnt">63
</span><span class="lnt">64
</span><span class="lnt">65
</span><span class="lnt">66
</span></code></pre></td>
<td class="lntd">
<pre tabindex="0" class="chroma"><code class="language-css" data-lang="css"><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="nt">html</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl">  <span class="k">background</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="err">$</span><span class="n">light-grey</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl">  <span class="k">line-height</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="mf">1.6</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl">  <span class="k">letter-spacing</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="mf">.06</span><span class="kt">em</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span></span><span class="line hl"><span class="cl">  <span class="n">scroll-behavior</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="kc">smooth</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="p">}</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl">
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="nt">body</span><span class="o">,</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="nt">button</span><span class="o">,</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="nt">input</span><span class="o">,</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="nt">select</span><span class="o">,</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="nt">textarea</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl">  <span class="k">color</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="err">$</span><span class="kc">text</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl">  <span class="k">font-family</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="err">$</span><span class="n">fonts</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="p">}</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl">
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="nt">pre</span><span class="o">,</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="nt">code</span><span class="o">,</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="nt">pre</span> <span class="nt">tt</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl">  <span class="k">font-family</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="err">$</span><span class="n">code-fonts</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="p">}</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl">
</span></span><span class="line hl"><span class="cl"><span class="nt">pre</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span></span><span class="line hl"><span class="cl">  <span class="k">padding</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="mf">.7</span><span class="kt">em</span> <span class="mf">1.1</span><span class="kt">em</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span></span><span class="line hl"><span class="cl">  <span class="k">overflow</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="kc">auto</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span></span><span class="line hl"><span class="cl">  <span class="k">font-size</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="mf">.9</span><span class="kt">em</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span></span><span class="line hl"><span class="cl">  <span class="k">line-height</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="mf">1.5</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span></span><span class="line hl"><span class="cl">  <span class="k">letter-spacing</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="kc">normal</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span></span><span class="line hl"><span class="cl">  <span class="k">white-space</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="kc">pre</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span></span><span class="line hl"><span class="cl">  <span class="k">color</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="mh">#eee</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span></span><span class="line hl"><span class="cl">  <span class="k">background</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="err">$</span><span class="kc">midnightblue</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span></span><span class="line hl"><span class="cl">  <span class="k">border-radius</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="mi">4</span><span class="kt">px</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span></span><span class="line hl"><span class="cl">  <span class="err">//</span> <span class="kp">-webkit-</span><span class="n">overflow-scrolling</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="n">touch</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl">
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl">  <span class="err">code</span> <span class="err">{</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl">    <span class="k">padding</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="mi">0</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl">    <span class="k">margin</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="mi">0</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl">    <span class="k">background</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="err">$</span><span class="kc">midnightblue</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl">  <span class="p">}</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="err">}</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl">
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="nt">code</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl">  <span class="k">color</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="mh">#eee</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl">  <span class="k">background</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="err">$</span><span class="n">highlight-grey</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl">  <span class="k">border-radius</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="mi">3</span><span class="kt">px</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl">  <span class="k">padding</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="mi">0</span> <span class="mi">3</span><span class="kt">px</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl">  <span class="k">margin</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="mi">0</span> <span class="mi">4</span><span class="kt">px</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl">  <span class="k">word-wrap</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="kc">break-word</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl">  <span class="k">letter-spacing</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="kc">normal</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="p">}</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl">
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="nt">blockquote</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl">  <span class="k">border-left</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="mf">.25</span><span class="kt">em</span> <span class="kc">solid</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl">  <span class="k">margin</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="mi">1</span><span class="kt">em</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl">  <span class="k">padding</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="mi">0</span> <span class="mi">1</span><span class="kt">em</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl">  <span class="k">font-style</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="kc">italic</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl">
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl">  <span class="err">cite</span> <span class="err">{</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl">    <span class="k">font-weight</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="kc">bold</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl">    <span class="k">font-style</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="kc">normal</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl">
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl">    <span class="err">&amp;::before</span> <span class="err">{</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl">      <span class="k">content</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="s2">&#34;—— &#34;</span><span class="p">;</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl">    <span class="p">}</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl">  <span class="err">}</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="err">}</span></span></span></code></pre></td></tr></table>
</div>
</div>
<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
<hr>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>From <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Apple">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Apple</a>&#160;<a href="#fnref:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:2">
<p>LaTeX is supported by Mathjax&hellip; which I don&rsquo;t have enabled because it&rsquo;s heavy and I&rsquo;m not doing theory right now.&#160;<a href="#fnref:2" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
