<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Daggerheart on Tabletop Ergonomics</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/daggerheart/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Daggerheart on Tabletop Ergonomics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>CC BY-SA 4.0</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 09:42:29 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/daggerheart/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Tacticool Campaign Frame</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/tacticool-campaign-frame/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 09:42:29 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/tacticool-campaign-frame/</guid>
      <description>In the near future, superpowered operatives that stop moving before they shoot seek to protect the world order from collapsing from threats inside and out.&#xA;The Pitch Tone and Feel Tacticool spy thriller Themes Spy thriller crap stress of being sharp who are we in a world that see us only as disposable tools what are you fighting for? Touchstones Valorant cinematics and lore Counter-Strike series, update pages and lore Metal Gear series replace &amp;ldquo;nanomachines&amp;rdquo; with &amp;ldquo;radianite&amp;rdquo; Rainbow Six Siege more gameplay and character moments, not the lore (it&amp;rsquo;s dumb) clips from esports tournaments xcom reboot that one episode of secret level about the korean tac shooter Overview todo: proper noun bank</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>You can fix 5e!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/you-can-fix-5e/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 14:53:32 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/you-can-fix-5e/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s start with some background &amp;ndash; I&amp;rsquo;ve taken a somewhat unusual route to arrive here. Technically, the first RPG I was exposed to was D&amp;amp;D 3E, but the first RPG I actually read and fell in love with was Risus. Note that Risus has a drastically different approach to mechanics and style compared to other traditional RPG&amp;rsquo;s: it&amp;rsquo;s a rules-light comedy game. Despite almost zero experience with running games, I printed out its six pages and had an incredible session on a camping trip with crazy, collaborative worldbuilding.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
